FRANK LUSE

SOFTWARE & DATA ENGINEER

EXPERTISE

Python, Pandas, Numpy MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS Javascript, HTML, CSS Illustrator, Photoshop React.js, Node.js GraphQL

EDUCATION

BA IN ECONOMICS
BA IN SOCIOLOGY

The University of Kansas Honors Program

2017 - 2021 ; CGPA: 3.96

OTHER

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish

VOLUNTEERING

Kansas Permaculture Institute Boy Scouts of America KU Campus Beautification Initiative

ACHIEVEMENTS

Eagle Scout Honors Distinction

CONTACT

Frank Luse 1111 Indiana St Apt 319 Lawrence, KS 66044

Email: fluse9@gmail.com Phone: (773) 383-1129

PROFILE

I am a young software engineer and entrepreneur with experience in a fast-paced startup. I had sole responsibility for all data engineering and successfully oversaw product and business development resulting in getting a product to market. With experience in software and a strong knowledge of statistics, I specialize in developing ready-to-ship web applications and data pipelines.

EXPERIENCE

TERRAFARM | FROM OCT 2019 - Present Co-Founder and Chief Executive Officer

- · Led 4 engineering teams and 1 design team from development to launch
- Developed an in-home vertical farm OS using C++ and Python that controls farm actuators and accesses database systems in real time
- Created a user-web application in React.js, Node.js, and GraphQL that allows customers to record what they plant and harvest and control certain actuators
- Constructed real time data pipelines to store thousands of customer and farm data points every day using AWS hosted PostgreSQL and MongoDB instances

THE UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS | FROM JAN 2019 - MAY 2020 Math Tutor - Applied Statistics

- · Tutored small groups of up to 5 students in elementary and applied statistics
- Guided students through course material, created practice problems, helped students improve their skills in probability, statistical analysis, and regression

PROJECTS

HONORS THESIS IN SOCIOLOGY | FROM AUG 2020 - Present

• Studied the effectiveness of OECD countries' stimulus programs in the 2020 recession using OLS linear regression and logistic regression models

AUTOMATED STOCK TRADING BOT | FROM OCT 2020 - DEC 2020

- Used Pandas, Numpy, and OLS regression to find predictors of stock returns
- Developed a Python bot to execute trades on Robinhood & Alpaca using triple momentum, divergence, and relative strength strategies

JARVIS PERSONAL ASSISTANT | FROM DEC 2020 - Present

 Created a personal assistant using Python and natural language processing that interprets commands and queries websites for its responses

FLUSE (MUSIC PRODUCER) | FROM AUG 2016 - Present

- · Composed, recorded, and produced original songs and remixes
- · Created logos, album art, and promotional materials
- · Achieved over 1 million streams on all streaming platforms combined